Mss.B.L265
American Philosophical Society
- Series VIII. Miscellaneous
  - "Bee Library of the late Rev. L. L. Langstroth.", >1885 October; 1.0 p.
    Typescript, with handwritten corrections. Sixty-one titles dating to 1579; mostly in chronological order.
  - Correspondence. Mickwitz, R. to Schramm, Jacob R., 1951 December 2; 2.0 p.
    Regarding bee-keeping in Finland. Mickwitz is Chairman of "The Langstroth Club (in Finland)".
  - Stokes, Everard. "Sonnet--To Langstroth"., 1.0 p.
    From "Poems of a Bee-Keeper" (Princeton University Press, 1947).
- Series IX. Photographs, 4.0 Photograph(s); A sample of the photographs available from the L. L. (Lorenzo Lorraine) Langstroth papers.
  - Lorenzo Lorraine Langstroth formal portrait, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Formal portrait mounted on carte de visite.
  - Lorenzo Lorraine Langstroth, full length, informal, seated outside, 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Langstroth holding movable-frame beehive, seated on stool, building and plants in background.
  - Lorenzo Lorraine Langstroth, full length, informal, standing outside, 1.0 Photograph(s); Langstroth, standing outside with walking cane, touching tree with left hand, building and trees in background.
  - Lorenzo Lorraine Langstroth, half length, formal, seated, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 view portrait of Langstroth.
- OVERSIZE
  - [Series I. Correspondence]
    - Aspinwall, [ ] [Langstroth to], 1888 December 14; 1.0 p.
  - [Series II. Legal Papers]
    - Contract. L.L. Langstroth with Joseph Bealz., undated; 1.0 p.
      Regarding Bealz's manufacturing of patented hive forms.
    - Patent (Drawing), 1852 October 5 [1860 July 18]; 1.0 item
      Drawing to accompany: True Copy of Patent issued to L. L. Langstroth, 5 October 1852, No. 9300, "Improvement in bee-hives". Copy by U.S. Patent Office, 18 July 1860.
  - [Series III. Legal Papers. Court Documents and Papers]
    - Otis v. King, 1871 November 2; 14.0 leaves.
      U.S. Circuit Court. Roswell C. Otis v. Homer A. King. Amended answer. Letterpress.
    - Otis v. King, 1871 November 7; 17.0 leaves.
      [U.S. Circuit Court, Southern District of Ohio.] Roswell C. Otis v. Homer A. King. Copy of Mrs. Jane A. Townley Deposition as far as taken. Letterpress; pages mechanically enumerated 762, and all odd numbers from 765 through 793.
    - Otis v. King, 1873 April 19; 19.0 leaves.
      U.S. Circuit Court, Southern District of Ohio. Roswell C. Otis v. Homer A. King. Depositions of Freeman Cary taken on the part of Complainant at Cincinnati, April 19 1873. Letterpress. Page 1 of deposition is absent.
    - Otis v. King, 1873 May 1; 14.0 leaves.
      U.S. Circuit Court, Southern District of Ohio. Roswell C. Otis v. Homer A. King. Deposition of A[dam]. W. Maxwell taken on the part of Complainant at Cincinnat[i] May 1st 1873. Letterpress.
    - Otis v. King, 1873 May 1; 14.0 leaves.
      U.S. Circuit Court, Southern District of Ohio. Roswell C. Otis v. Homer A. King. Deposition of A[dam]. W. Maxwell taken on the part of Complainant at Cincinnati May 1st 1873. Letterpress. [Duplicate?]
    - Otis v. King, 1873 May 10; 31.0 leaves.
      U.S. Circuit Court, Southern District of Ohio. Roswell C. Otis v. Homer A. King. Copy of depositions of Levi Fish and Maria A. Robinson. Letterpress.
    - Otis v. King, 1873 May 14; 9.0 leaves.
      U.S. Circuit Court, Southern District of Ohio. Roswell C. Otis v. Homer A. King. Testimony taken on the part of Complainant at New York City--14 of May 1873 Letterpress. [Page 3 is duplicated.]
    - Otis v. King, 1873 May 22, 23; 33.0 leaves.
      U.S. Circuit Court, Southern District of Ohio. Roswell C. Otis v. Homer A. King. Depositions of witnesses taken at Cincinnati May 22nd & 23rd 1873 on behalf of Complainant. Letterpress.
    - Otis v. King, 1873 May 22, 23; 36.0 leaves.
      U.S. Circuit Court, Southern District of Ohio. Roswell C. Otis v. Homer A. King. Testimony of Witnesses on behalf of Complaintant taken at Cinti May 22 & 23rd 1873. Letterpress.
    - Otis v. King, 1873 May 26; 45.0 leaves.
      U.S. Circuit Court, Southern District of Ohio. Roswell C. Otis v. Homer A. King. Cross-examination of H. F. Putnam, taken by consent at Cincinnati, Ohio, May 26 - 27 1873. Letterpress (some leaves fragmentary).
    - Testimonial re court proceedings (?). Written on long, fragile leaves; some recto and verso; one leaf fragmentary. Unsigned., undated; 11.0 leaves.
  - [Series VI. Manuscripts by L. L. Langstroth]
    - "The Drone says he has been shamefully slandered and demands his day in Court.", undated; 4.0 leaves.
    - "For the Bee Keepers Magazine", [1881?]; 1.0 leaves.
    - Miscellaneous documents folded together, 1860, undated; 6.0 leaves.
      Various manuscript leaves, including one headed "Recollections of an old Bee-Keeper" [autobiographical]. Annotated slip found with these: "This was all folded together--so left it all together" [presumably when collection was acquired by APS in 1954].
      Also included is small printed tract by S. B. Parsons, acknowledging a request for prices for "Italian Bees". Included in the tract is a reprinting of "The Domestication of Italian Bees" from the New-York Evening Post; an excerpt from "Country Gentleman"; and "Extract of a Letter from L. L. Langstroth, dated Feb. 22, 1860" from Bienenzeitung (1859 February 28).
  - [Series VII. Extracts from Publications]
    - "Advertizement", "Artificial Combs", and "Queen Nursery"
      On one sheet: [1] "Extracts from 1st edition published at Northamtpon, Mass. May, 1852--Advertizement L.L. Langstroth's Moveable Comb Hive. Patented October 5th, 1852." [2] "Artificial Combs- p. 80". [3] "Queen Nursery- p. 235".
  - [Series VIII. Miscellaneous]
    - Diploma, 1872 April 12; 1.0 leaves.
      Diploma, in Italian, to "Onorevole Signore", from Associazione Centrale d'Incoraggiamento per l'Apicoltura in Italia (Milano).